### Janhvi Tiwari

Junior Cyber Security Engineer | Developer

A quick learner with a passion for computers and the ambition to make a significant contribution. One year of exposure with DevOps implementation, fundamental security operations, and web development. Interested in cyber strategy consultancy and cyber intelligence to aid in the design and execution of cyber security strategies and systems. Also combining security and machine learning to construct robust and effective security solution.

tjanhvi1805@gmail.com

github.com/ms-hacker404



mslazyhacker.wixsite.com/cyber-security-info/

linkedin.com/in/janhvi-tiwari-a2a371201

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Cyber Security Trainee - Traineeship** Mossé Cyber Security Institute

December 2022 - May 2023

Achievements/Tasks

- Conducted **network vulnerability scans** and web application penetration testing using Metasploit, identifying critical security weaknesses and recommending improvements.
- Demonstrated strong proficiency in Open Source Intelligence (OSINT), gathering and analyzing valuable information to enhance threat detection and response.
- Extensively contributed to red teaming exercises, utilizing offensive security tools to simulate cyber-attacks and evaluate defense capabilities.

#### Jr Cloud DevOps Engineer - Full Time **Turquoic**

December 2020 - March 2021.

Achievements/Tasks

- Implemented CI/CD pipelines with tools like GitLab CI/CD, or CircleCI. resulting in 15% faster and more reliable application releases.
- Attended agile ceremonies including daily standups, sprint planning, sprint reviews, while working with the development team to implement JIRA dashboards to improve transparency.
- Assisted in cost optimization efforts by analyzing cloud resource usage, leading to 5% reduction in monthly infrastructure costs.

#### **Web Developer - Internship Turquoic**

July 2020 - December 2020,

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed, tested, and implemented web applications using ReactJs,CSS JavaScript, while consistently achieving client requirements, expectations, and timelines.
- Developed multiple front-end websites using WordPress and other editing Software, improving user experience.
- Maintained code repositories using GIT and researched industry trends and best practices to improve code reviews.

### **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

#### Library Concierge - Part Time **RMIT University**

March 2023 - Present

- Provided assistance or referral advice to Library users while within public collections spaces, maintaining a helpful and friendly demeanor at all times.
- Perform group or team Collection maintenance projects.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor of Science: Computer Science**

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology

March 2021 - Present, Melbourne, Victoria

#### CORE SKILLS

**Security Operations** 

Web Development

DevOps

**Object Oriented Programing** 

**Risk Assessments** 

**Innovative Thinking** 

**Analytical Acumen** 

**Relationship Building** 

**Excellent Communication** 

**Creative Problem Solving** 

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### **Cyber Security**

Wireshark, Kali Linux, Penetration Testing, InfoSec, **Vulnerability Assessment** 

#### **Programming Languages / Web** Development

Java, Python, JavaScript, ReactJs

#### **Security & Administration**

TCP/IP, DNS/DHCP, LAN/WAN, IPv4, Firewalls, VMware vSphere

#### **Cloud Computing & Automation**

Microsoft Azure, AWS

#### **Operating Systems**

Windows Server 2013-2016. Ubuntu

#### **APIs & Integrations**

REST APIs, JSON, Web API

### **Agile Tools & Incident Management**

**JIRA** 

#### Shift Runner – Part Time Dominos

January 2022 - Present

- Promoted to in-store shift runner within a month of service in recognition of guick learning and adaptability.
- Managing a team of 5 and overseeing the daily operations including sales, billing, inventory, and complaints management.
- Consistently recognized for outstanding analytical, communication and organizational skills while multitasking and successfully competing priorities in high-pressure situations.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Redesign Website - Capstone Project

Led a team of five overseeing the redesign of a client's website.
Managed client communication and project leadership to ensure seamless collaboration and exceed client expectations.

**Skills Demonstrated** – React.js, Node.js, JavaScript, Effective Communication, Strong Leadership

#### Cyber Security Information - Personal Project

 Maintaining a website to write blogs on cybersecurity topics, news, and online safety strategies to raise cyber awareness among people.

**Skills Demonstrated** – Ability to Research, Writing Skills, Communication, Management, Basic of Cyber Security

#### Healthy Wellbeing Website - University Pair Project

Final Score: High Distinction

 Developed a website within 15 days that promotes healthy wellbeing with a personal meal planner.

**Skills Demonstrated -** Full stack development, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, PHP, MySQL

#### Neighborhood Doctors - University Team Project

Final Score: High Distinction

 Simulated a Scrum software design and development team to build a web application that provides online Telemedicine services while working in sprints and delivering a demonstration and presentation.

**Skills Demonstrated** – Scrum Management, Java, Springboot, Rest API, Teamwork, Presentation Delivery, Object Oriented Programing

#### Secure Minecraft API – University Team Project

Final Score: 29/30

 Built an efficient Chosen Ciphertext Attack (CCA) secure protocol (which used block cipher) to provide confidentiality and message integrity at the same time.

**Skills Demonstrated** – Wireshark, Python, REST API, Report Writing, Object Oriented Programing

#### **EXTRA CURRICULAR**

#### Program Mentor (March 2023 - Present)

**Grad Girl VIC** 

 Managing a group of 20 girls and guiding them through their career and professional journeys, as well as providing academic assistance.

#### Peer Mentor (March 2023 - June 2023)

**RMIT University** 

 Selected as a Peer Mentor at RMIT for my outstanding academic achievements, providing guidance and support to junior students by assisting them with assignments and addressing their doubts.

#### Industry Liaison Officer (May 2022 – March 2023)

**RUSU Women's Collective** 

- Recognized for adept leadership, fostering trust with stakeholders,

motivating club members to excel in event delivery, and mentoring and coaching female students in career and professional development.

# Innovation Project Team Member (August 2021 -February 2022)

Google Developer Student Club - RMIT

Collaborating with selected club members to develop a solution to the ongoing problems in the community like Zoom Fatigue.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING**

#### **IBM Cyber Threat Intelligence Coursera**

August 2022 - December 2022

Learning about data protection and threat intelligence

# **Deloitte STEM Connect Virtual Experience Program Forage**

August 2022

Gained valuable experience exploring tasks in: Data, Code, Cyber

## PwC Switzerland Cybersecurity Consulting Virtual Experience Program Forage

August 2022

Integrated Information Defense, performed risk assessment

#### TryHackMe - Cyber Security Training

Gathering hands-on Cyber security training through realworld scenarios and won badges also ranked at top 12%

## Mastercard Cybersecurity Virtual Internship Forage

April 2022

Designed a phishing email simulation for the Security Awareness team.

#### Microsoft Azure Al Fundamentals

February 2022

# Institute For Design of Electrical Measuring Instruments (IDEMI) Cyber Security & Ethical Hacking

December 2021

Learnt about cyber forensics and introduction to network fundamentals

#### Internshala Ethical Hacking Training

November 2021

Introduction to ethical hacking learnt briefly about Top 10 OWASP

#### REFERENCES

References available upon request.